Finding Aid for the Brian Urquhart Collection of Material about Ralph Bunche, ca. 1932-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Palestine 3., July-August 1948.; [Box 6, 3 folders]
  - First draft of The Count Bernadotte Mediation on Palestine in 1948 Part 3. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Record of telephone conversations Cordier - R.J. Bunche., July 1-9, 1948. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche written notes., July-August 1948. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Papers, cables from the Security Council of the UN Hebrew Press Review., June 5, 1948. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Draft of Establishment of United Nations Truce Supervision Organization., June 13, 1967. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - UN Bulletin. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Security Council official records. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cables, letters U.N., Secretary General - R.J. Bunche., June 1967, 1948. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cables with instructions to observers, UN Mediator - Secretary General. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Palestine., September 1948.; [Box 7, 4 folders]
  - Oversize telegrams from Public Record Office., 1948. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Transcript of R.J. Bunche's written notes., September 1948. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Transcript of R.J. Bunche's written notes., September 18-30, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cables UN Security Council. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Excerpts from Yearbook of UN., 1948. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Papers on the assassination of Bernadotte. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Confidential paper, The assassination of Count Bernadotte., 1971. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Letter: L. Lachenschmidt and R.J. Bunche., June 20, 1968. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Mutual Broadcasting Company's broadcast in Haifa., September 21, 1948.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cables: Haifa - UN. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Papers: Mediator on Palestine, UN Security Council, Haifa, Secretary General. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Excerpts from New York Review., May 1992. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Palestine., October 1948.; [Box 7, 3 folders]
  - Documents about refugee policy and Bernadotte. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche's written notes., October 1948. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cables: UN Security Council., October 1948. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Exerpts from Keesing's Contemporary Archives., November 27-December 4, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Report: UN and Haifa., October 14. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - UN Bulletin., November 1948. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Excerpts from Azcarate's Mission in Palestine., 1948-1952. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche's statement to First Committee by R.J. Bunche., October 15. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - CBS interview w/R.J. Bunche., October 17. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche to: F. Harris (); R.J. Bunche & NAACP (); The Nation's F.Kirchway & T. Lie ()., March 4, 1968 October 22, 1948 November December 1948. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Transcript of conversation between A- C- and X and Mr.B.., October 21, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - UN Security Council's preliminary report on Palestine., October 25, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche's statement to Security Council meeting re the Negev situation., October 28, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Palestine 4., November-December 1948.; [Boxes 7-8, 3 folders]
  - Report: Reasons for Conclusions on Frontiers. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - R.J. Bunche's written notes., November-December 1948. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - French Broadcasting System., November 3, 1948.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Paris T.V. broadcast., November 6, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - UN press statement., November 8, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Reports: R.J. Bunche to Secretary General of UN re truce in Lebanon Sector (); Paris press conference ()., November 6, 1948 November 9, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Memorandum: Negev Provisional Demarcation Lines., November 13, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Resolution of Palestinian question by Security Council, UN., November 17, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Report by Swiss Radio. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Statement by R.J. Bunche to First Committee., November 25, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Press release on Palestine problem., November 25, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Cables: Haifa - UN Supplemental memorandum by R.J. Bunche on difficulties in 4 November resolution on the Negev., November 26, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche's further report on deaths of UN Observers Queru & Jeannel., November 30, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche's supplementary report on Palestine. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Progress reports on 4 November resolution on the Negev. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche - Haifa., December 6 and December 10, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche - Israel's Ministry for Foreign Affairs. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Transjordan's response to R.J. Bunche., December 9, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's memo re Ben-Gurion., December 7, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Keesing's Contemp. Archives., January 15-22, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Provisional Government of Israel's note to R.J. Bunche., December 9, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Letter: Eben - R.J. Bunche., December 9, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's committee with Government of Lebanon., December 15, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Cables: UN - Paris., December 1948. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Palestine., January-February 1949.; [Box 8, 4 folders]
  - Cables: personnel matters., January-March 1949. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Lists: R.J. Bunche photos, (); press releases ()., January-September 1949 February-August 1949. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Yearbook of UN., 1948-1949. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Original document B. General F.P. Henderson's How to write an Armistice. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes:., January 7, 1949-February 27, 1949, February 28, 1949-April 18, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Document Restrictions on movements of UN Observers. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Document: UN R.J. Bunche and Transjordan & Rhodes. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - UN cables on Egypt, Lebanon, Palestine, Rhodes, U.K., and Israel., January 1949. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., January-February 1949. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Cables: UN Security Council; R.J. Bunche - Secretary General; R.J. Bunche, Rhodes - Reedman ()., February 1949. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., February 1949. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Cables: Personal & Confidential R.J. Bunche, Rhodes-Secretary General; Excerpts Keesing's Archives., February 26-March 5, August 27-September 3, July 9-15, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., February 1949. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche's speech from Rhodes re armistice agreement. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Eytan's 3 Nights at Shuneh. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - A.S. Eban's statement re armistice negotiations at Rhodes (); UN Bulletin article: Milestone to Peace in Palestine ()., February 23, 1949 March 15, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Top Secret dispatch: R.J. Bunche-Acheson. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Cable: UN re Israel-Egypt armistice. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Palestine., March-April 1949.; [Box 8, 4 folders]
  - List of resolutions by General Assembly., 1947-1974. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., January 17-31 and February 28-April 18, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - List of cablegrams., March 1-21, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Excerpts from Yearbook of UN., 1947-1974, bulk. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Statement of R.J. Bunche at First Joint Formal Meeting of Israeli-TransJordan Armistice Negotiations., March 4, 1949.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Cables (Personal and confidential): R.J. Bunche-Secretary General, R.J. Bunche-Cordier. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., March 1949. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - UN Bulletin article: Further Progress in Palestine. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche - UN re S. Negev (); urgent and confidential R.J. Bunche - Secretary General., March 22, 1949 March 30, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche - U.N., R.J. Bunche - Secretary General, strictly confidential R.J. Bunche-Cordier, Beirut re Israeli forces & Syria., April 7, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., April 1949. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - R.J. Bunche's statement at Israeli-Transjordan signing., April 3, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Document: Present Incidents Between Israel & Syria., April 6, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-S. Papaioannou., April 8, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Cables: U.N.-Riley, R.J. Bunche - Vigier, R.J. Bunche-Riley. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - R.J. Bunche's press release re Palestine., April 18, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Dinner Meeting in Honor of Dr. R.J. Bunche., May 9, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., April 1949. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Letters: Urquhart - Barbara (); Urquhart - S. Aryeh ()., December 5, 1984 November 1984. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Palestine., May-December 1949.; [Box 9, 3 folders]
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche and: Vigier, Ethridge, Mohn (Tel Aviv). (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche - A.S. (); Lie - Eban ()., Eban May 10, 1949 May 23, 1949. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Speech by W. O'Dwyer for R.J. Bunche., May 17, 1949.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Draft article Armistice Demarcation Lines. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., May-December 1949. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche and: Mohn, Vigier, Riley. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche - A.S.Eban, re information arriving from Middle East., June 22, 1949. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Informal lecture by R.J. Bunche on Palestine., June 16, 1949. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's replies to comments at Israeli-Syrian Armistice Conference., June 26, 1949. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., June 1949. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche to: Vigier, Riley, Mohn., July 1949. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Citation: R.J. Bunche as Spingarn Medalist., July 17, 1949. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Draft article on Armistice Demarcation Lines. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Israeli-Syrian Armistice signed today., July 20, 1949.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Statement by R.J. Bunche for Security Council., August 4, 1949. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Draft resolution by delegations of Canada & France., August 8, 1949. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche to: O. Dajany, T. Lie, Taylor ( re UN Economic Survey Mission for Middle East)., September 1949. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Palestine (Addenda)., 1949.; [Box 9, 2 folders]
  - Time Warner Transcript () Egypt & Israel., 1949. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Cease-fire agreement for Los Angeles' Bloods & Crips., June 17, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche & W.M. Watson., July 23, 1964. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Arab-Israeli Armistice Statements., 1952-1966. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Special Report French Language., September 12, 1969. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche disclaimer re 1949 talks at Rhodes., February 29, 1968.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letters: (); Urquhart (); B.L. DeRidder (); Faris El-Khouri, Secretary General & Riley ()., March 1968 1967 April 1951 November 1951. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - A Short Memory by M. Jack., October 17, 1969. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Reports: Secretary General re complaints Armistice between Israel & Syria; re Security Council's resolution (); Palestine Question ()., January 11, 1955 April 4, 1956 May 9, 1956. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Original pamphlet: Developing Peace-Keeping Capacity of UN by R.N. Gardner., 1964. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Confidential Report: Possible Basis for strengthening United Nations Truce Supervision Organization in Syria-Israel Demilitarized Zone., March 16, 1960. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Strictly confidential memo: R.J. Bunche & Chief of Staff, United Nations Truce Supervision Organization., March 14, 1960. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- The Palestine Question at the UN., [Box 9, 1 folder]
  - Lengthy report: The Palestine Question at the UN including Annual Reports of the Secretary General. Outlines of the work of various organs of the UN., 1946-1957. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- ., 1950-1953.; [Boxes 9-10, 7 folders]
  - Chatam House publication,; Memo from Lake Success., March 1952 and June 1953 January 13, 1950. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - UN Yearbook., 1950. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche Notes., March-April 1950. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Private & confidential memo re R.J. Bunche's visit to London., April 3, 1950. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Letter: Secretary General to Security Council President re members list of panel for inquiry & conciliation., March 30, 1950. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Keesing's Contemp. Archives., July 1-8 and 15-22, April 22-29, and November 11-18, 1950. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - UN Bulletin article: Use of Conciliators Endorsed by Council. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., June-December 1950. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Secretary General's annual report., 1950-1951. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - UN Bulletin article: Dr. Bunche awarded the Nobel Peace Prize., October 15, 1950. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Pauline Frederick's interview: NBC-TV., February 1969. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - UN Bulletin article: Palestine Issues Again to Fore., November 15, 1950. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - UN Bulletin articles: Recommendations for Settling Outstanding Palestine Issues (); Security Council Resolution; R.J. Bunche Notes: Nobel Peace Prize trip including Typescript (carbon)., December 1, 1950. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - R.J. Bunche's Nobel Prize statement of acceptance, Some Reflections of Peace in our Time. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Motion Picture Offers., 1951-1954. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Personal correspondence UN members. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., June, August, December 1951. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences - R.J. Bunche., March 28, 1951. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche's speech w/Astaire. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Ebony article re R.J. Bunche & Hollywood., 1951. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Excerpts from Keesing's and UN Bulletin., 1951. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Keesing's., June 9-16, 1951. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - UN Bulletin., May 15, 1951. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - UN Yearbook., 1951. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Secretary General's annual report., 1951-1952. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Time article., July 9, 1951. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Keesing's., July 14-21, 1951, September 29-October 6, 1951, December 1-8, 1951. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - UN Bulletin., August 1 and 15, September 1, 1951. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Private memorandum for Secretary General., November 29, 1951. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Article re R.J. Bunche's honorary college degrees., 1951. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Article: Saturday Evening Post: Sinister Doings at UN., November 17, 1951. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., November-December 1951. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - New York Times index., 1952. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., January, March-December 1952. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Trygve Lie's papers of Secretary General: TV interview w/U.N. correspondents., March 18, 1952. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - UN Yearbook., 1952. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Secretary General's annual report,; Keesing's., 1952-1953 February 14-21, 1953. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - UN Yearbook., 1953. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes re India trip () & I.P.R. Luncheon ()., January 1953 March 10, 1953. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Keesing's., April 4-11, May 2-September 19-26, October 17-24, December 5-12, 1953. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche's Toward Peace and Freedom., April 22, 1953. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - UN Bulletin Dag Hammarskjold's Together in our concern, our hopes, and our determination., October 1, 1953. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Saturday Evening Post Sinister doings at U.N.., November 17, 1951. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Security Council Official records., November 1953. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Loyalty Hearings., 1954.; [Boxes 10-11, 5 folders]
  - H.E. Stassen's speech ABC broadcast., December 27, 1951. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Daily Worker re R.J. Bunche imperialist aide., October 2, 1950. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche letters re loyalty., 1952. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Keesing's., February 7-14, 1953. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - T. Lie's statement re communist infiltration of UN., October 13, 1952. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Acts. of U.S. Citizens in UN by E. Wallach. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Secretary General note to correspondents re internal security., October 23 and January 2, 1953. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Information circular from Secretary General re advisory panel., January 16, 1953. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., February-November 1953. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - World Today's 8th Assembly of U.N.., February 1954. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Secretary General's annual report., July 1, 1954-June 15, 1955. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche interview., April 13, 1966. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., January-September 1954. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Loyalty Board and Chronology of Loyalty Saga. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Personal & Confidential letter R.J. Bunche - P.J. Gerety () & International Organization Employs Loyalty Board's interrogatory., January 13, 1954. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Memo: R.J. Bunche - Gerig re M. Yergan., March 22, 1945. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Letters: P. Robeson-L. Pasvolsky (); M. Yergan-R.J. Bunche ()., December 29, 1944 December 13, 1938.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche's comments on Race:America's Social Barrier. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - FBI memo re council African Affairs, M. Yergan ()., May 19, 1945. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche notes w/Hammarskjold., 1954. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche's extensive correspondence re Marxist affiliation if any., Typescript (carbon) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche statements, articles on democracy., 1936, 1940, 1950. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche notes re Loyalty Board Hearings., May 1954. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Various articles re R.J. Bunche and Loyalty hearings., 1954. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Non-Sectarian Anti-Nazi League's Castroviejo Meeting., May 29, 1954. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Various letters of support for R.J. Bunche., 1954. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., August 1954. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Confidential meeting Archibald Roosevelt's home () re Bunche Project., August 13, 1954. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Press conference., August 19, 1954. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Strictly Confidential memo re Ralph Bunche file., September 2, 1954. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-O.S. Strauss II., 1954. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Extensive report re R.J. Bunche & communist leanings. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., October-December 1954. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Confidential report re Alliance Incorporated, World Today 9th Assembly of U.N.., December 8, 1954. February 1955. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Letters: support for R.J. Bunche., 1955-1959. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Suez Canal Historical Background., [Box 11, 1 folder]
  - International Review Service pamphlets., 1955-1967, bulk. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Arab-Israel Conflict & the U.N.
    The Suez Canal: Nationalization, Invasion, International Action.
    UNEF: The UN Emergency Force: Origins, Functions, Continuing Perspectives.
    The UN Emergency Force (UNEF) 1955- Creation, Evolution, End of Mission-1967.
- Suez Canal., pre-1956; January-September 1956.; [Boxes 11-12, 3 folders]
  - Draft of Chapter 9: The Suez Crisis. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Synopsis of Security Council Resolutions re Israel and Arab neighbors., October 25, 1956. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Chronology of Suez-Hungary special sessions., September-November 1956. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - General Assembly Resolutions () 7th Session., 1953 February 24-April 23, 1953, 1953-1961. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Yearbook of UN., 1954 and 1955. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Keesing's., January 30-February 6, April 3-10, 1954, April 23-30, August 27-September 3, 1955, January 14-21, February 26-March 5, 1956. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche Notes re South American Trip., February 10-March 3, 1955 & March 12-April 8, 1955. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Strictly personal & confidential note: Secretary General-R.J. Bunche ()., July 15, 1955. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Confidential memo., December 5, 1955. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Keesing's., September 10-17, November 5-19, 1955, April 7-14, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Secretary General's annual report., June 16, 1955-June 15, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - New York Times index., 1956. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Yearbook of UN., 1956. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche notes 1956 w/Hammarskjold., April 7-14, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Cease-Fire Correspondence., April 12, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Keesing's., May 26, 1956-June 2, July 14-21, October 20-27, July 28, 1956-August 11, September 22-29, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Secretary General's statement re Palestine incidents., September 13, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Note Verbale., September 14, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Suez Canal 1., October-December 1956.; [Box 12, 4 folders]
  - Keesing's., October 6-13, November 3-10, December 8-15, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - U.N. Review article: Requirements for a Settlement of the Suez Canal Situation. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Original U.N. Review (vol.3 no.5)., November 1956. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Strictly Confidential: Meeting of the Advisory Committee on UN Emergency Force November 20, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Keesing's., January 12-19, January 26, 1957-February 2, 1957 and January 17-24, November 24-December 1, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Egypt requests UN Assistance., November 18, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - UN memo: Secretary General-R.J. Bunche., November 1956. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche interview., April 13, 1966. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Resolutions: 997-1003. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - W.R. Frye's A UN Peace Force., 1957. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Press statements by Secretary General on Middle East and UN Emergency Force., November 1956. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cables from Secretary General. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Most Secret summary record of Secretary General, his Advisors, & Delegation of Israel., November 28, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cables: Secretary General & Burns & Leary & R.J. Bunche & Seggen & Martola. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Press releases re: Secretary General & Burns (); Wheeler & Suez Canal (); Secretary General on Suez Canal clearance ()., March 12, 1956 December 7, 1956 December 18, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Press Release: Secretary General before General Assembly., December 21, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - UN Emergency Force: Creation, Evolution, End of Mission ()., 1956-1967. (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Suez Canal 2., January-March 1957.; [Box 12, 4 folders]
  - Between Arab and Israeli: Chapter 13 Israel Invades Egypt: October 29, 1956. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Eisenhower The White House Years: Chapter 7 Renewed Tension in the Middle East. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - View From the UN: Chapter 11 Arab-Israeli War of 1956. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Keesing's., February 2-September 1957. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Keesing's., January 26, 1957-February 9, 1957. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche & Burns & Robles & Secretary General & Stavropoulos & Ballah & Cordier & Reddy. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Israeli Withdrawal from Sinai., January 5, 1957. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-A.H. Sulzberger., January 14, 1957.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Cables: Stavropoulos & Seggen. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Keesing's., March 23-30, 1957. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Cables: Secretary General & Burns & Stavropoulos & Cordier & Reddy. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Letters: Secretary General-A.Eban, Jacob-R.J. Bunche. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Secretary General statements & notes to correspondents & press releases. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Second draft letter to Participating States., February 25, 1957. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Keesing's., March 23-30, May 18-25, February 9-16, 1957. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Press releases: statements by Secretary General., March 1, 4, 1957. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Statement H.C. Lodge., March 1, 1957. (Box 12, Folder 9)